<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Sorry, Rawyer</title>
    <link>http://blog.sory.biz/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Sorry, Rawyer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 21:41:51 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://blog.sory.biz/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Interviews I&#39;ve Gone and Done</title>
      <link>http://blog.sory.biz/posts/interviews-ive-done/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 21:41:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.sory.biz/posts/interviews-ive-done/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been a full-time software engineer for about 5 years. I&amp;rsquo;m currently in my second full-time engineering job. I&amp;rsquo;ve interviewed at dozens of companies and have been given about four job offers. Over the last 6 or 7 years I&amp;rsquo;ve come across a lot of interview questions. Sometimes I&amp;rsquo;ve enjoyed the puzzles, sometimes it was like a sentient &amp;ldquo;cracking the coding interview&amp;rdquo; was making fun of me. Some interviews were near-misses (I think) and others made me question my choice of career.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Another Tangent: Trying to Make a Theremin</title>
      <link>http://blog.sory.biz/posts/theremini-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 May 2018 10:34:42 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.sory.biz/posts/theremini-1/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve finally created something tangible. So far, my definition of success at RC has been amorphous and open-ended: if I&amp;rsquo;ve learned, I&amp;rsquo;ve succeeded. That hasn&amp;rsquo;t changed, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t realize how much I missed seeing (or, in this case, hearing) real output from something I wrote.
My idea for this project was to build a theremin. At its simplest, a theremin is an electronic instrument that produces a sine wave based on the position of a players hands with respect to two antennae.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing Matplotlib</title>
      <link>http://blog.sory.biz/posts/matplotlib-gah/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 01:17:34 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.sory.biz/posts/matplotlib-gah/</guid>
      <description>Just how good is MP3, anyway? I wondered this during my recent struggle with decoding MP3 files. File formats are chosen based on tradeoffs, and with digital media the tradeoffs tend to coalesce around two variables: quality and size. Inspired by a few recent experiments at RC to visualize data loss in digital media, I wanted to answer this question for myself. My idea is to compare the spectrograms of different audio formats to get a sense of which frequencies are being left out by codec compression techniques.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Decoding MP3s, Volume 3: I Think I&#39;ve Got What I Need</title>
      <link>http://blog.sory.biz/posts/decoding-mp3-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Apr 2018 10:10:52 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.sory.biz/posts/decoding-mp3-3/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to abandon my project to write an MP3 decoder. This is the most significant project that I&amp;rsquo;ve officially declared myself &amp;ldquo;done&amp;rdquo; with at RC, and as such I feel I need to justify the decision to myself. By &amp;ldquo;most significant&amp;rdquo; I really mean &amp;ldquo;spent more than a couple hours on&amp;rdquo;, but while at RC it seems important to have a clear sense of what it takes for me to consider myself being &amp;ldquo;done&amp;rdquo; with something.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some Number of Weeks Into RC, Part 1: 3</title>
      <link>http://blog.sory.biz/posts/some-weeks-into-rc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Apr 2018 15:35:13 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.sory.biz/posts/some-weeks-into-rc/</guid>
      <description>My batch at RC (Spring 2) started three weeks ago. I knew my experience at and with RC would fluctuate wildly. The community, the space, what other people are working on, what I&amp;rsquo;m working on, my reactions to and feelings about each of those things, these are all constantly in motion. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure I&amp;rsquo;m at a point to make much sense of it, but I at least feel somewhat prepared to do some introspection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Decoding MP3s, Volume 2: A Portrait of the Audio as a Compressed Bit Stream</title>
      <link>http://blog.sory.biz/posts/decoding-mp3-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2018 22:08:45 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.sory.biz/posts/decoding-mp3-2/</guid>
      <description>The other day, I wrote about the process of how I arrived at decoding MP3s in Python. Today, I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to create a rough outline for the next few MP3 posts. The idea is to keep the next few posts light. I&amp;rsquo;m just going to pull from my notes, skip fact-checking, and hit &amp;ldquo;post&amp;rdquo;. I&amp;rsquo;ll start today with a very basic outline of what MP3s are made of. I&amp;rsquo;ll save the more intricate details for later posts, by which time I hope to actually understand what I&amp;rsquo;m saying.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Decoding MP3s, Volume 1: I Guess I&#39;m Decoding MP3s Now</title>
      <link>http://blog.sory.biz/posts/decoding-mp3-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2018 23:31:19 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.sory.biz/posts/decoding-mp3-1/</guid>
      <description>In which I find out that I don&amp;rsquo;t know how MP3 decoding works
Coming into the Recurse Center, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d found a solid project: move my music and videos into cloud storage and create a media player that can move stuff to and from local disk without the user knowing or caring. This is similar to Spotifys approach of letting users keep certain media on their device while streaming everything else.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>There Must Be Some Mistake</title>
      <link>http://blog.sory.biz/posts/some-mistake/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Apr 2018 12:27:45 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.sory.biz/posts/some-mistake/</guid>
      <description>In addition to being a novel by Frederick Barthelme, &amp;ldquo;there must be some mistake&amp;rdquo; is usually my first thought upon hearing that something good has happened to me. So it is with my ending up at the Recurse Center. RC is a strange place where people are happy and kind and encouraging and incredibly smart. Maybe not all of these things all at once all the time, but they&amp;rsquo;re most things most of the time and it&amp;rsquo;s truly remarkable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Actual First Post</title>
      <link>http://blog.sory.biz/posts/actual-first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Apr 2018 21:26:03 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.sory.biz/posts/actual-first-post/</guid>
      <description>In which I try to actually start a blog
In 2010, my dad got me a domain name for my birthday. When he told me about it, he warned that he set it up in such a way as to motivate me to actually do something with my gift. There was some header text and a photo. If my memory serves me correctly, the header was &amp;ldquo;Rory&amp;rsquo;s Dad is amazing!&amp;rdquo; The text was red, the background was black.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>