<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Sorry, Rawyer</title>
    <link>http://blog.sory.biz/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Sorry, Rawyer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2018 23:31:19 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://blog.sory.biz/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Decoding MP3s, Volume 1: I Guess I&#39;m Decoding MP3s Now</title>
      <link>http://blog.sory.biz/posts/decoding-mp3-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2018 23:31:19 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.sory.biz/posts/decoding-mp3-1/</guid>
      <description>In which I find out that I don&amp;rsquo;t know how MP3 decoding works
Coming into the Recurse Center, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d found a solid project: move my music and videos into cloud storage and create a media player that can move stuff to and from local disk without the user knowing or caring. This is similar to Spotifys approach of letting users keep certain media on their device while streaming everything else.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>There Must Be Some Mistake</title>
      <link>http://blog.sory.biz/posts/some-mistake/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Apr 2018 12:27:45 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.sory.biz/posts/some-mistake/</guid>
      <description>In addition to being a novel by Frederick Barthelme, &amp;ldquo;there must be some mistake&amp;rdquo; is usually my first thought upon hearing that something good has happened to me. So it is with my ending up at the Recurse Center. RC is a strange place where people are happy and kind and encouraging and incredibly smart. Maybe not all of these things all at once all the time, but they&amp;rsquo;re most things most of the time and it&amp;rsquo;s truly remarkable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Actual First Post</title>
      <link>http://blog.sory.biz/posts/actual-first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Apr 2018 21:26:03 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.sory.biz/posts/actual-first-post/</guid>
      <description>In which I try to actually start a blog
In 2010, my dad got me a domain name for my birthday. When he told me about it, he warned that he set it up in such a way as to motivate me to actually do something with my gift. There was some header text and a photo. If my memory serves me correctly, the header was &amp;ldquo;Rory&amp;rsquo;s Dad is amazing!&amp;rdquo; The text was red, the background was black.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>